Guide to the Peter H. Klopfer Papers, 1957-1980s UA.29.02.0104
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Peter H. Klopfer papers
1957-1980s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Klopfer, Peter H.
UA.29.02.0104
58.5 Linear Feet
Peter Klopfer is a Professor in the Department of Biology (previously known as Zoology). This collection contains ledger books and information relating to grants and research proposals, ranging in date from 1957-1971.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Peter H. Klopfer Papers were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1977 and 2015.
Biographical/Historical note
Peter H. Klopfer was born August 9, 1930 in Berlin, Germany. He earned his B. A. degree (with honors) from the University of California at Los Angeles in 1952 and his Ph.D. from Yale University in 1957. In 1958, Professor Klopfer came to Duke as Assistant Professor in the Department of Zoology (now Dept. of Biology). In 1967, he was promoted to Professor. His area of research is animal behavior and behavioral ecology. His areas of interests are maternal attachment, aggression and species diversity. He was instrumental in starting the primate center at Duke. As of 2006, Klopfer is retired and is Professor Emeritus. However, he continues to do research, with his current project focusing on sleep and hibernation behavior in prosimian primates.
Scope and Contents note
Contains materials from the many grants Professor Klopfer received to fund his animal-behavior research. Included are ledger books, correspondence, research and grant paperwork, including applications. The collection ranges in date from 1957-1971.
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004,
Duke University Archives
.
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004,
Duke University Archives
.
Duke University. Department of Zoology; Klopfer, Peter H.; Duke University. Department of Biology.; Duke University -- Faculty
- Accession of 1977
  - Grant Material, circa 1969 (Box 1)
  - Grant Material, circa 1970 (Box 1)
  - Grant Material, circa 1971 (Box 1)
  - Grant Application (Box 1)
  - Grant Proposal Information, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Stimulus Preferences and Imprinting, by Klopfer, 1967 (Box 1)
  - National Science Foundation Grant Proposal, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Electronics Technician, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Grant Award and Budget, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Contract and Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Contracts and Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 1)
  - Margarita Laboratory, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Grant Proposal, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - BSGG, Summer 1969 (Box 1)
  - ONR, prior to 1967 (Box 1)
  - ASB Bulletin, 1969 July (Box 1)
  - NASA contract, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - NASA, circa 1968 (Box 1)
  - New support sought, 1971 (Box 1)
  - NASA, circa 1972 (Box 1)
  - NC Heart Association (Box 1)
  - Grant Materials, 1968 (Box 1)
  - NASA, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Grant Information, circa 1971 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 1)
  - Ledgers, 1957-1970 (Box 1)
- Accession UA2015-0060, 1960s-1980s; 2
  - Correspondence, A-J (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, J-T (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, U-Z; Grants (Box 4)
  - Grants, circa 1980s (Box 5)
  - Grants, circa 1980s (Box 6)
  - Grants, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 7)
  - Grants, EKG sheets, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 8)
  - University Correspondence through 1982 (Box 9)
  - Research, 1960s-1970s (Box 10)
  - Research, 1960s (Box 11)
  - Research, 1960s, punch data cards, large rolled dot matrix printouts (Box 12)
  - Research 1960s, Correspondence A-H (Box 13)
  - Correspondence H-W, Student Correspondence A-H (Box 14)
  - Student Correspondence H-W (Box 15)
  - Dead correspondence, S-Z; old grants (Box 16)
  - Student Files A-H and assorted (Box 17)
  - Students, assorted, and publication/manuscript drafts and correspondence (Box 18)
  - Students, A-H (Box 19)
  - Students, L-W (Box 20)
  - Students, A-Z (Box 21)
  - Students, B-Z (Box 22)
  - Students B-Z (Box 23)
  - The Book: Drafts, Notes and Correspondence (Box 24)
  - Correspondence A-S (Box 25)
  - Novelty data and tests; Galagos;L. Variegatus (Box 26)
  - L. Macaco, L. Variegatus: Mo-Young (Box 27)
  - Bilbo and Balin L. Catta Maternal studies; L. Variegatus Raw Data (Box 28)
  - Bilbo and Balin L. Catta Maternal studies; L. Variegatus Raw Data (Box 29)
  - L. Catta; L. Fulvus (Box 30)
  - L. Fulvus Calypso; L. F. Albifrons; Bathsheba; Miriam; David; Ishmael (Box 31)
  - L. F. Albifrons: Bathsheba, Lisa, Sal, Red Child (Box 32)
  - observational notebooks; some writing drafts (Box 33)
  - observational notebooks: L. Fulvus and much more (Box 34)
  - observational data; L. Catta activity cycle data; Romulus and Remus tally sheets; Cato and Bilbo tally sheets (Box 35)
  - observational data and research notes (Box 36)
  - knitting needle cataloging system and related books listing articles; sheets for the Jonker machine (Box 37)
  - knitting needle cataloging system (Box 38)
- Accession UA2016-0005, undated
  - Goat Watching Society t-shirts